Guide to the First Congregational Church of Portland records 1849-2016
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Groups, 1863-2015; Series B
  - Silver Circle, Subseries 22
    - Meeting minutes, 1941 January 9 (Box-folder 44/8)
    - Meeting minutes and annual reports, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 44/9)
    - Meeting minutes, 1944 February 10 - circa 1947 (Box-folder 44/10)
    - Meeting minutes, 1954 September 30 - 1958 May (Box-folder 44/11)
    - Reports, 1914-1932; undated (Box-folder 45/1)
    - Resolution, 1934 November 8 (Box-folder 45/2)
    - Roll book, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 45/3)
    - Roster, 1941 (Box-folder 45/4)
  - Social Action Committee, Subseries 23
    Also called Division of Social Action.
    - Roster, 1941 (Box-folder 45/5)
    - Roster, 1942 (Box-folder 45/6)
    - Roster, 1943 (Box-folder 45/7)
  - Proposal to create a Social Justice Commission, 2000 (Box-folder 45/8)
  - Social Justice Commission meeting minutes, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 45/9)
  - Social Justice Commission meeting minutes and reports, 2012-2014 (Box-folder 45/10)
  - Sunday Morning Design Committee records, 1993 (Box-folder 45/11)
  - Survey Committee - Letter re church survey, 1986 February 18 (Box-folder 45/12)
  - Women's Fellowship, Subseries 24
    First known as Women's Association or Woman's Association. For records relating to the Silver Circle, see Subseries 22.
    - Attendance records, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 45/13)
    - Description of circle activities, 1953 June 7 (Box-folder 45/14)
    - "On the Circle Circuit" newsletters, 1954 November - 1955 June (Box-folder 45/15)
    - Annual reports of circles, circa 1949-1958 (Box-folder 45/16)
    - Circle membership list, 1958 September (Box-folder 45/17)
    - Circle 5 meeting minutes and treasurer's reports, 1950 October - 1954 May (Box-folder 45/18)
    - Circle 5 financial ephemera, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 45/19)
    - Circle 5 rosters, circa 1954; undated (Box-folder 45/20)
    - Circle I meeting minutes, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 45/21)
    - Circle I meeting minutes, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 45/22)
    - Circle I meeting minutes, 1958 November - 1961 May (Box-folder 45/23)
    - Notes re Circle I meetings, circa 1954 (Box-folder 45/24)
    - Esther Circle records, 1961 September - 1974 April (Box-folder 45/25)
      Primarily meeting minutes.
    - History of Friendship Circle, undated (Box-folder 45/26)
    - Correspondence re Friendship Circle, 1953 (Box-folder 45/27)
    - Friendship Circle roster, 1955 February 23 (Box-folder 45/28)
    - Martha Circle records, 1961 September - 1966 April (Box-folder 45/29)
    - Sewing Circle - Christmas card and list of birthdays, circa 1965 (Box-folder 45/30)
    - Clippings re Women's Fellowship, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 45/31)
    - Clippings re Women's Fellowship, 1965 (Box-folder 45/32)
    - Constitution, 1946 December (Box-folder 45/33)
    - Constitution and standing rules, circa 1952, 1952 May-December (Box-folder 45/34)
    - Constitution, 1959 (Box-folder 45/35)
    - Amendments to constitution, 1966 July 6 (Box-folder 45/36)
    - Revised constitution, undated (Box-folder 45/37)
    - Directory/calendar booklet for 1943-1944 (Box-folder 45/38)
    - Directory and program, 1948 (Box-folder 46/1)
    - Directory/calendar booklets, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 46/2)
    - Directory/calendar booklets, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 46/3)
    - Directory/calendar booklet for 1967-1968 (Box-folder 46/4)
    - Event flyers, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 46/5)
    - Event flyers, programs, and announcements, 1972-1974; undated (Box-folder 46/6)
    - Events - Invitation for bazaar, 1921 (Box-folder 46/7)
    - Eulogy for Anna S. Warren, 1925 October 7 (Box-folder 46/8)
    - Finances - Check register book, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 46/9)
    - Financial ledger, 1934-1950 (Box-folder 46/10)
    - Financial ledger, 1951 January - 1955 October (Box-folder 46/11)
    - Financial ledger, 1955 November - 1961 June (Box-folder 46/12)
    - Finances - Memorial Fund contributions, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 47/1)
    - Financial records, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 47/2)
    - Financial records, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 47/3)
    - Financial records, 1960, 1969 (Box-folder 47/4)
    - Financial reports and notes, 1919-1945, undated (Box-folder 47/5)
    - Financial report for 1920, circa 1921 (Box-folder 47/6)
    - Finances - Annual statements and notes, 1957-1959; 1967 (Box-folder 47/7)
    - Kitchen policy, 1947 October 7 (Box-folder 47/8)
    - Kitchen management policy, 1952 January (Box-folder 47/9)
    - Leadership training camp, 1955 July (Box-folder 47/10)
    - Lenten communion service programs, 1962; 1969-1969 (Box-folder 47/11)
    - Lenten and Lord's Supper communion programs, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 47/12)
    - Meeting minutes, 1926 January 11 (Box-folder 47/13)
    - Minutes book, 1939-1949 (Box-folder Box 138)
      Also includes some loose papers that had been paperclipped inside book.
    - Meeting minutes, 1949 November-December (Box-folder 47/14)
    - Meeting minutes, 1950 (Box-folder 47/15)
    - Meeting minutes, 1951 (Box-folder 47/16)
    - Meeting minutes, 1952 (Box-folder 47/17)
    - Meeting minutes, 1953 (Box-folder 47/18)
    - Meeting minutes, 1954 (Box-folder 47/19)
    - Meeting minutes, 1955 (Box-folder 47/20)
    - Meeting minutes, 1956 (Box-folder 47/21)
    - Meeting minutes, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 47/22)
    - Meeting minutes, 1959 (Box-folder 47/23)
    - Meeting minutes, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 47/24)
    - Meeting minutes, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 47/25)
    - Meeting minutes, 1966-1968 May (Box-folder 47/26)
    - Program for March 1, 1961 meeting, 1961 February 23 (Box-folder 47/27)
    - Memorandum, 1952 October 8 (Box-folder 47/28)
    - Newsletters, 1953 September - 1956 May (Box-folder 47/29)
    - Nominating Committee recommendation, circa 1952 (Box-folder 47/30)
    - Annual reports for 1919, 1921, circa 1920, circa 1922 (Box-folder 47/31)
    - Reports, circa 1923-1926 (Box-folder 47/32)
    - Report, circa 1925 (Box-folder 47/33)
    - Reports and ephemera, 1941-1947 (Box-folder 47/34)
      Had been paperclipped to page of minutes book in Box 138.
    - Annual report, 1947 January 15 (Box-folder 47/35)
    - Annual reports, 1950 May (Box-folder 47/36)
    - Reports, 1952 May (Box-folder 48/1)
    - Reports, 1953 (Box-folder 48/2)
    - Annual reports, 1954 (Box-folder 48/3)
    - Reports, 1955 (Box-folder 48/4)
    - Reports, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 48/5)
    - Reports, 1960-1962; 1968 (Box-folder 48/6)
    - Retreat, 1955 July (Box-folder 48/7)
    - Roster of Red Cross project participants, circa 1945 (Box-folder 48/8)
    - Roster, 1943 (Box-folder 48/9)
    - Roster, 1963 (Box-folder 48/10)
    - Publicity scrapbook, 1939-1949 (Box-folder 48/11)
    - Typescript of October 1946 article re Women's Association changing its name to Women's Fellowship, undated (Box-folder 48/12)
    - "Working Principles of the Women's Fellowship", 1966 May 10 (Box-folder 48/13)
  - Woman's Home Missionary Union, Subseries 25
    Initially called Women's Congregational Home Missionary Union of Oregon.
    - Financial summaries and check, 1893-1894; 1897 (Box-folder 48/14)
    - Financial accounts ledger, 1893 October 26 - 1895 September 18 (Box-folder 48/15)
    - Rally programs, 1896; 1902 (Box-folder 48/16)
    - Annual report, 1904 (Box-folder 48/17)
  - Women's League - Report for 1917, 1918 January 10
  - Woman's Missionary Society, Subseries 26
    Also called Ladies' Missionary Society.
    - Research files (Box-folder 48/19)
    - Clipping, "The Last Three Years of the Woman's Boards", 1910 October 1 (Box-folder 48/20)
    - Program calendars, 1903-1904 (Box-folder 48/21)
    - Constitution, undated (Box-folder 48/22)
      From before 1923.
    - Constitution, 1934 May 16 (Box-folder 48/23)
    - Correspondence - Letter from Elizabeth Eggert, 1934 April (Box-folder 48/24)
    - Notices of Easter thankofferings, 1906-1922 (Box-folder 48/25)
    - Easter thankoffering notices/programs, 1930-1933 (Box-folder 48/26)
    - Finances - Bequest of Sarah E. Clarke Estate, 1926 (Box-folder 48/27)
    - Finance book, 1899-1906 (Box-folder 48/28)
    - Finance book, 1906-1915 (Box-folder 48/29)
    - Finance book, 1915-1922 (Box-folder 49/1)
    - Financial records, circa 1918; 1929-1930; 1934 (Box-folder 49/2)
    - List of names and dates, circa 1930 (Box-folder 49/3)
      Possibly a roster of group presidents' terms
    - Minutes book, 1890-1898 (Box-folder 49/4)
      Includes a copy of the 1883 constitution of the Ladies' Missionary Society.
    - Minutes book, 1898 October 4 - 1904 October 12 (Box-folder 49/5)
    - Minutes book, 1904 October 19 - 1910 June 15 (Box-folder 49/6)
    - Minutes book, 1910 October - 1917 November (Box-folder 49/7)
      Also includes loose papers and reports that had been pinned or clipped to book pages.
    - Minutes book, 1918 January 16 - 1929 January 16 (Box-folder 49/8)
      Also includes loose papers that had been placed within or clipped to book pages.
    - Minutes, 1929-1937 May (Box-folder 50/1)
    - Minutes book, 1937 June 16 - 1939 December 16 (Box-folder 50/2)
    - Nominations, 1936 (Box-folder 50/3)
    - Annual reports, circa 1918-1931 (Box-folder 50/4)
  - Women's Pastoral Department report for 1920, circa 1921 (Box-folder 50/5)
  - Women's Social Action Committee report for 1952-1953 (Box-folder 50/6)
  - Worship Commission, Subseries 27
    Known in the 1930s as the Department of Worship and Fellowship, and from the 1940s to 1994 as Spiritual Life Commission.
    See also Minutes for Music Committee and Spiritual Life Commission joint meetings, 35/13.
    - Clippings re Worship Commission, 1999 (Box-folder 50/7)
    - Section of bylaws re Spiritual Life Commission, circa 1983 (Box-folder 50/8)
    - Committee assignments and rosters, 1952-1956 (Box-folder 50/9)
    - Correspondence and memos, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 50/10)
    - Correspondence and memos, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 50/11)
    - Correspondence and memos, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 50/12)
    - Memos and suggestions from Reverend Royald V. Caldwell, 1960; 1966 (Box-folder 50/13)
    - Memo to Samaritan Counseling Center re Spiritual Life Commission officers, 1986 March 17 (Box-folder 50/14)
    - Memo to Commission re special youth worship service, 1986 September 29 (Box-folder 50/15)
    - Minutes book, 1931-1936 May (Box-folder 50/16)
    - Meeting minutes, 1940 June-1943 (Box-folder 50/17)
    - Meeting minutes, 1944-1948 January (Box-folder 50/18)
    - Meeting minutes, 1949 (Box-folder 50/19)
    - Meeting minutes, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 50/20)
    - Meeting minutes, 1953-1955 January (Box-folder 50/21)
    - Meeting minutes, 1960 May 24; 1965 February-October (Box-folder 50/22)
    - Meeting minutes, 1966 (Box-folder 50/23)
    - Meeting minutes, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 50/24)
    - Meeting minutes, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 50/25)
    - Meeting minutes, 1972-1974 March, 1975 September 8 (Box-folder 51/1)
    - Meeting minutes, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 51/2)
    - Meeting minutes, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 51/3)
    - Meeting minutes, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 51/4)
    - Meeting minutes, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 51/5)
    - Meeting minutes, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 51/6)
    - Meeting minutes, 1990-1993 March (Box-folder 51/7)
    - Meeting minutes, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 51/8)
    - Meeting minutes, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 51/9)
    - Meeting minutes, 2000-2003 (Box-folder 51/10)
    - Meeting minutes and notices, 2006-2009 (Box-folder 51/11)
    - Meeting minutes and reports, 2011 October-2014 (Box-folder 51/12)
    - Organizational meeting notes, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 51/13)
    - Organization of duties/activities, circa 1960 (Box-folder 51/14)
    - Annual report for 1969, circa 1970 (Box-folder 51/15)
    - Goals from planning retreat, 1973 June 11 (Box-folder 51/16)
    - Retreat at Camp Adams, 1988 February-March (Box-folder 51/17)
    - List of Spiritual Renewal Retreat participants, 1991 April (Box-folder 51/18)
    - Rosters, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 51/19)
    - Rosters, 1970-1973; 1978 (Box-folder 51/20)
    - Rosters, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 51/21)
    - Script for Palm Sunday service, 1984 April 8 (Box-folder 51/22)
    - Statement of purpose, circa 1979 (Box-folder 51/23)
    - Documents re statement of purpose and objectives, 1983 (Box-folder 51/24)
    - Documents re mission statement, 1987 (Box-folder 51/25)
  - Young Adult Fellowship/Century Club records, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 51/26)
  - Young Adult Fellowship records, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 51/27)
  - Young Married Couples roster, 1968 August 28 (Box-folder 51/28)
  - Young People's Department reports, 1923-1926 (Box-folder 51/29)
  - Youth Advisory Council meeting agenda, 1996 July 16 (Box-folder 51/30)
  - Youth group event notices, 1933 (Box-folder 51/31)
  - Flyers for youth group events, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 51/32)
  - Unidentified committee minutes, undated (Box-folder 51/33)
- History and memorabilia, 1899-circa 2010; Series C
  - Anniversary celebrations, Subseries 1
    - Ephemera and research files re 50th anniversary celebration, 1901; undated (Box-folder 52/1)
    - Materials and research files re 80th anniversary celebration, 1931; undated (Box-folder 52/2)
    - Book of memories used for 80th and 90th anniversaries, 1931; 1941 (Box-folder 143/1)
    - Materials and research files re 90th anniversary celebration, 1941; undated (Box-folder 52/3)
    - Materials and research files re centennial celebration, 1951; undated (Box-folder 52/4)
    - Centennial celebration - Georgia E. Higgins' memory book, 1951 (Box-folder 52/5)
    - Centennial celebration - Donna John's memory book, 1951 (Box-folder 52/6)
    - Centennial celebration - Nancy Ross' memory book, 1951 (Box-folder 52/7)
    - Centennial celebration - unidentified pupil's memory book, 1951 (Box-folder 52/8)
    - Centennial celebration - commemorative stamp set, 1951 (Box-folder 52/9)
    - Book of remembrance used for centennial and 125th anniversaries, 1951; 1976 (Box-folder Box 142)
    - Address given by Arthur W. Austin for 105th anniversary, 1956 April 24 (Box-folder 52/10)
    - 110th anniversary celebration, 1961 (Box-folder 52/11)
    - Invitation and program for 122nd anniversary celebration, 1973 (Box-folder 52/12)
    - 125th anniversary celebration, 1976 (Box-folder 52/13)
    - Invitation letter to 130th anniversary celebration, 1981 June 2 (Box-folder 53/1)
    - 136th anniversary celebration, 1987 (Box-folder 53/2)
    - 138th anniversary celebration, 1989 (Box-folder 53/3)
    - 140th anniversary celebration, 1991 (Box-folder 53/4)
    - 140th anniversary celebration - remarks by Elmer Moke on church history, 1991 January-February (Box-folder 53/5)
    - Sesquicentennial celebration, 2001 (Box-folder 53/6)
    - Church building centennial, 1995 (Box-folder 53/7)
  - Research files re annual reports (Box-folder 53/8)
  - History of church by Abbie M. Cardwell, 1904 January (Box-folder 53/9)
  - Research files and clippings re church history (Box-folder 53/10)
  - Research files and clippings re history of church buildings (Box-folder 53/11)
  - History of church building by Elaine Molksness, 1988 May (Box-folder 53/12)
  - Materials re naming of Council Crest, 1902; 1928; 1958; undated (Box-folder 53/13, 112/8, 113/2)
  - Influenza epidemic, 1919 January (Box-folder 53/14)
  - Notes re Ladies' Aid Society and Women's Association history, undated (Box-folder 53/15)
  - Scrapbook, 1885-1960 (Box-folder Box 140)
  - Scrapbook, 1925-1955 (Box-folder 139/2)
  - Georgia E. Higgins' scrapbook, circa 1925-1974 (Box-folder Box 144)
  - Scrapbook, 1961-1984 (Box-folder Box 141)
  - History of Sunday School, Subseries 2
    Includes pioneer members' letters to church historian Mattie E. (Mrs. W. D.) Palmer on the subject.
    - Notes, correspondence, and reminiscences re history of Sunday School, 1902-1962; undated (Box-folder 53/16)
    - Letter from James F. Failing to Mattie E. (Mrs. W. D.) Palmer, 1903 January 16 (Box-folder 53/17)
      Also includes undated typescript of letter.
    - Letter from James F. Failing to Mattie E. (Mrs. W. D.) Palmer, 1903 April 17 (Box-folder 53/18)
    - Notes by Matilda Farrington re her time teaching Sunday School, circa 1933 (Box-folder 53/19)
    - Letter from Mary Gray to Hugh Evans (Box-folder 53/20)
    - Letter from George H. Himes to Mattie E. Palmer, 1902 December 22 (Box-folder 53/21)
    - Letter from George H. Himes to Mattie E. Palmer, 1903 January 1 (Box-folder 53/22)
    - Typescript of letter from M. A. Hodgon, 1902 June 28 (Box-folder 53/23)
      Date is when original letter was written; date of transcription is unknown.
    - Letter from W. H. Phillips re his work as Sunday School superintendent, circa 1920 (Box-folder 53/24)
    - History of Sunday School by Mattie E. Palmer, 1903 January 10 (Box-folder 53/25)
    - Typescript of Sophia Pratt's reminiscences, undated (Box-folder 53/26)
      Reminiscences were the basis for sketch located in 111/30.
    - Letter from G. Shindler to Mattie E. Palmer, 1902 December 14 (Box-folder 53/27)
  - "That Church with the Tower: Highlights of Our History", 2001 (Box-folder 54/1)
    Book written for sesquicentennial of church.
  - Correspondence and records re "That Church with the Tower", circa 2000-2002 (Box-folder 54/2)
  - Forum presentations on "That Church with the Tower", 2001 (Box-folder 54/3)
  - Status as United Church of Christ church, 1947-circa 2010 (Box-folder 54/4)
  - Vietnam War, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 54/5)
    Consists of letters which Reverend Royald V. Caldwell wrote to church members serving in the Armed Forces.
  - Explanations of various women's groups, 1954 July (Box-folder 54/6)
  - World War I, 1917-1919; 2006 (Box-folder 54/7)
    Includes Honor Roll of church members serving sent to the church in 2006, and accompanying letter.
  - World War II, circa 1940-1946 (Box-folder 54/8)
  - World War II - Files on church members in service, circa 1941-1946 (Box-folder 54/9-54/10)
    Includes some photographs and newspaper clippings.
- Membership statistics, 1867-2012; Series D
  Includes reports given regarding new membership gains and losses.
  - Research files re number of church members (Box-folder 54/11)
  - Book of absentees; memberships, 1924; 1925-1927 (Box-folder 54/12)
  - Attendance records, 1901-1902 (Box-folder 112/9)
  - Baptismal records, 1923-1943 (Box-folder 55/1)
  - Membership book, circa 1910-1913 (Box-folder 55/2)
  - Membership book, 1910-1925 (Box-folder 55/3)
    Also includes 1925 memorial tribute to Sarah Eleanor Clarke.
  - Membership book, 1920; 1923 (Box-folder 55/4)
  - Membership book, 1927-1930 (Box-folder 55/5)
  - Clipping re church membership numbers in 1880, 1930 (Box-folder 55/6)
  - Directories, 1886; 1888-1890 (Box-folder 55/7)
  - Directory and annual report, 1891 (Box-folder 55/8)
  - Annual report and directory, 1892 (Box-folder 55/9)
  - Annual report and directory, 1895 (Box-folder 55/10)
  - Yearbook and directory, 1896 (Box-folder 55/11)
  - Directory, 1902 (Box-folder 56/1)
  - Directory, 1904 (Box-folder 56/2)
  - Directory, 1906 (Box-folder 56/3)
  - Directory, 1912 (Box-folder 56/4)
  - Combined volume of 1902, 1904, 1906, and 1912 directories, circa 1912 (Box-folder 56/5)
  - Directory of church officers, 1933 (Box-folder 56/6)
  - Membership ledger, 1867-1913 (Box-folder 147/1)
  - Membership ledger, 1924 November - 1930 February (Box-folder 147/2)
  - List of pre-1890 members compiled by George H. Himes, 1903 (Box-folder 56/7)
  - Manual, 1867 (Box-folder 56/8)
  - Manual, 1885 (Box-folder 56/9)
  - Manual, 1895 (Box-folder 56/10)
  - Manuals, 1906 (Box-folder 56/11)
  - Manual and directory, 1921 (Box-folder 56/12)
  - Register, circa 1943-1986 (Box-folder 57/1)
  - Register, circa 1960-2001 (Box-folder Box 146)
  - Chairman of Ushers' annual report, 1918 January 10 (Box-folder 56/13)
  - Church Clerk's reports, 1918-1926 (Box-folder 56/14)
  - Church Clerk's reports, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 56/15)
  - Annual statistical reports, 1868-1885 (Box-folder 56/16)
  - Statistical reports for 1932-1939, 1933-1940 (Box-folder 57/2)
  - Statistical reports for 1940-1947, 1941-1948 (Box-folder 57/3)
  - Membership roll, 1924 (Box-folder 57/4)
  - Roster of members, circa 1895 (Box-folder 57/5)
  - Roster of officers, 1923; 1925 (Box-folder 57/6)
  - Committee/commission roster, 1953 (Box-folder 57/7)
  - Committee/commission rosters, 1993; 1996 (Box-folder 57/8)
  - Committee/commission roster, 2012 (Box-folder 57/9)
  - List of past moderators, 1994 (Box-folder 57/10)
  - Statistical analyses of membership, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 57/11)
  - Statistical charts, 1930-1945 (Box-folder 57/12)
- Members, 1895-2011; Series E
  Documents, clippings, ephemera, and research files about notable members of the church.
  - Adams, Carrie B. (Box-folder 57/13)
  - Adams, Carrie B. - Music added to "Book of Memories" by Harriet Filch, and a note from Carrie Adams to Filch, 1935 (Box-folder 57/14)
  - Allen, Wayne W. (Box-folder 57/15)
  - Arnold, Katherine S. (Box-folder 57/16)
  - Bader, Allison (Box-folder 57/17)
  - Beach, Frank E. and family (Box-folder 57/18)
  - Bishop, Sarah (Box-folder 57/19)
  - Boos, Carol and family (Box-folder 57/20)
  - Cake, Ralph and ancestors (Box-folder 57/21)
  - Casterline, Polly (Box-folder 57/22)
  - Clapp, Frances B., Subseries 1
    Clapp worked as a missionary in Kyoto, Japan both before and after World War II.
    Subseries contains letters which Clapp wrote to her friends while in Japan and elsewhere.
    - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 57/23)
    - Book with Japanese cards inserted into pages, undated (Box-folder 98/5)
    - Letter and attached note, 1928 January 7 (Box-folder 57/24)
    - Letters, 1933-1941 (Box-folder 57/25)
    - Letter, 1934 September 30 (Box-folder 112/10)
    - Letter, 1937 September 7 (Box-folder 112/11)
      Letter alludes to conditions after the outbreak of the Second Sino-Japanese War.
    - Letters, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 58/1)
    - Letters, 1950-1954, undated (Box-folder 58/2)
    - Correspondence with Alta Blood, 1956 (Box-folder 58/3)
    - Japanese-language pamphlets on Christianity, circa 1955 (Box-folder 98/4)
      Had been placed in 1955-1956 scrapbooks.
    - Copy of "My Younger Days" by Joseph Hardy Neesima (Box-folder 58/4)
    - Scrapbook, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 98/1)
    - Scrapbooks, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 98/2-98/3, Box 145)
    - "A Shikoku Odyssey", 1931 (Box-folder 58/5)
      Account of Clapp's travels in Japan in March-April 1931.
  - Clark, Lee M. (Box-folder 58/6)
  - Crooks, Robert A., Senior (Box-folder 58/7)
  - Daggett, D. Leslie (Box-folder 58/8)
  - Davenport, Helen (Box-folder 58/9)
  - Derry, Ida Starkweather (Box-folder 58/10)
  - Duncan, Arthur (Box-folder 58/11)
  - Dressler, Margaret Dawn (Box-folder 58/12)
  - Dysart, John P. and Mathilde (Box-folder 58/13)
  - Eggert, Elizabeth Avery and Frederick, Subseries 2
    See Series B: Groups for Elizabeth Eggert's history of the Ladies Aid Society.
    - Research files and clippings (Box-folder 58/14)
    - Materials re the Eggerts' attendance at Second International Congregational Council, 1899 (Box-folder 58/15)
    - Materials re Congregational Church of Brooklyn honoring Frederick and Elizabeth Eggert, 1899 (Box-folder 58/16)
    - "Echoes from Great Assemblies," by Elizabeth Eggert, circa 1899 (Box-folder 58/17)
    - Note to Elizabeth Eggert from Howard N. Smith, 1907 October 17 (Box-folder 58/18)
  - Evans, Delia Beatrice (Box-folder 58/19)
  - Farnham, Mary Frances (Box-folder 58/20)
  - Gibson, Ray (Box-folder 58/21)
  - Gilbert, Harold S. and Bessie (Box-folder 58/22)
  - Gray, Mary (Box-folder 58/23)
  - Green, Helen (Box-folder 58/24)
  - Griswold, Graham (Box-folder 58/25)
  - Handsaker, J. J. (Box-folder 58/26)
  - Harper, Harry (Box-folder 58/27)
  - Hayward, Charles (Box-folder 58/28)
  - Hesselman, Helen (Box-folder 58/29)